# Upbound Group — Brand Guidelines

**Visual & verbal identity standards**
Version 1.0 · 2026

---

## Contents

1. Brand Foundation
2. Logo
3. Logo Usage & Misuse
4. Color Palette
5. Color Application
6. Typography
7. Voice & Tone
8. Imagery & Graphic Elements
9. Sub-Brands
10. Quick Reference

---

## 01 · Brand Foundation

Upbound Group is a modern, enterprise-focused organization built to elevate financial opportunity for all. Our brand expresses forward momentum, clarity, and confidence — a company that is optimistic and ambitious, but grounded and trustworthy.

### Mission

To elevate financial opportunity for all.

### Brand Personality

- **Forward-looking** — we move people and outcomes upward.
- **Confident, not loud** — authoritative without being aggressive.
- **Clear and accessible** — we make the complex feel simple.
- **Optimistic** — a sense of possibility runs through everything.

### Brand Idea: "Upbound"

The name is our north star. Every expression of the brand — visual or verbal — should reinforce a sense of upward motion, progress, and positive trajectory. When in doubt, ask: *does this move the audience upward?*

---

## 02 · Logo

The Upbound wordmark is the primary expression of our identity. It is set in a distinctive rounded sans-serif with a lowercase treatment that feels approachable, modern, and human. The wordmark should always appear as supplied — never redrawn or re-typed.

### Logo Variations

Use the version with the strongest contrast against its background. Full-color (green) is reserved for accents and small marks only — the wordmark itself stays black or white.

| Variation | Use on |
|---|---|
| Black wordmark | Light backgrounds (white, off-white) |
| White wordmark | Dark backgrounds (near black) |
| White wordmark | Deep Navy surfaces |

### Clear Space

Always maintain clear space around the wordmark equal to the height of the "u" in "upbound." Keep this area free of text, graphics, and other logos so the mark can breathe.

### Minimum Size

To preserve legibility, never reproduce the wordmark smaller than **24px** tall on screen or **0.35 inches** in print.

---

## 03 · Logo Usage & Misuse

Consistency protects the brand. The wordmark is a fixed asset — the following modifications are never permitted:

- ✕ Do not stretch, condense, or distort the proportions.
- ✕ Do not rotate or set the wordmark on an angle.
- ✕ Do not change the logo color outside the approved variations.
- ✕ Do not add drop shadows, outlines, gradients, or effects.
- ✕ Do not place the wordmark on a busy background with poor contrast.
- ✕ Do not re-type or substitute the wordmark with another font.
- ✕ Do not crop, recolor individual letters, or rearrange elements.

---

## 04 · Color Palette

Our palette pairs a bold, energetic green with deep, sophisticated darks. The green is the unmistakable signal of the brand; the darks provide the confident, premium foundation it sits against.

| Color | HEX | RGB | CMYK | Usage |
|---|---|---|---|---|
| **Upbound Green** | `#B3FF33` | 179, 255, 51 | 30, 0, 80, 0 | Signature accent. CTAs, highlights, key data, the brand dot. Use sparingly for maximum impact. |
| **Deep Navy** | `#35323D` | 53, 50, 61 | 75, 70, 55, 60 | Primary dark surface. Backgrounds, hero sections, headers. |
| **Near Black** | `#1A1A1A` | 26, 26, 26 | 0, 0, 0, 90 | Wordmark, primary body text, high-contrast backgrounds. |
| **Charcoal** | `#3A3A3B` | 58, 58, 59 | 0, 0, 0, 77 | Secondary dark surfaces and subtle depth layering. |
| **Cool Grey** | `#C3C2C5` | 195, 194, 197 | 0, 0, 0, 24 | Dividers, secondary text on dark, supporting panels. |
| **Off White** | `#F4F4F5` | 244, 244, 245 | 0, 0, 0, 4 | Light backgrounds and section fills. |

> **Note:** CMYK values are best-estimate conversions from RGB. For print, confirm against a proof with your printer.

---

## 05 · Color Application

### The 60 / 30 / 10 Rule

For balanced, on-brand compositions:

- **60%** — Dark foundation (Deep Navy, Near Black, Charcoal).
- **30%** — Neutrals (Off White, Cool Grey) for space and legibility.
- **10%** — Upbound Green as the accent. Never let green dominate a layout.

### Accessibility

Upbound Green is a bright accent, not a text color. Never set green text on white or light backgrounds — contrast is insufficient. Green works well as a background behind near-black text (as in buttons) or as a small accent on dark surfaces. Always meet WCAG AA (4.5:1) for body text.

### Do

- Use green for a single clear call-to-action per view.
- Set white or off-white text on navy and black surfaces.
- Use the green "dot" as a recurring signature accent.

### Don't

- Fill large areas with green or use multiple green elements competing for attention.
- Place green text on white, grey, or navy.
- Introduce colors outside this palette.

---

## 06 · Typography

The brand voice is expressed typographically through a two-font system: an expressive geometric sans for headlines and a neutral grotesque for text. Together they feel modern, confident, and highly legible — energetic where it counts and effortless to read everywhere else.

### Primary Typeface — Poppins

Poppins is our primary brand typeface. Its geometric construction and rounded terminals echo the "upbound" wordmark, giving headlines and display type a confident, optimistic, unmistakably-Upbound character. Use Poppins for headlines, display type, subheads, pull quotes, and any brand-forward moment.
**Recommended weights:** SemiBold and Bold for headings, Medium for subheads.

### Secondary Typeface — Inter

Inter is our secondary typeface, used for body copy, UI, captions, and long-form text. It is a neutral, highly legible grotesque that stays clean at small sizes and lets Poppins lead at the headline level. Pairing an expressive display face with a neutral text face keeps layouts energetic at the top and effortless to read throughout.

### System Fallbacks

When Poppins and Inter are unavailable — internal Office documents, email, or environments without the brand fonts installed — substitute system equivalents so nothing breaks: use **Arial** (or **Calibri**) in place of both. Fallbacks are for necessity only; use the true brand fonts wherever they can be embedded.

### Pairing Rules

- Poppins for headlines and display; Inter for body and captions. Never reverse this.
- Never use more than these two families in a single piece.
- Create hierarchy with weight and size — not by introducing new fonts.
- Keep body copy in a single weight of Inter for calm, readable text blocks.

### Type Scale

| Level | Style | Spec |
|---|---|---|
| **Display / H1** | Bold · sentence case | 40–56pt · tight leading |
| **Heading / H2** | Semibold | 24–32pt |
| **Subhead / H3** | Medium | 18–22pt |
| **Body** | Regular | 10–12pt · 1.4 line height |
| **Caption / Label** | Bold · all caps · tracked | 8–9pt |

---

## 07 · Voice & Tone

Upbound sounds like a confident, optimistic guide. We speak plainly, lead with the benefit to the reader, and always convey forward motion. Whether the audience is an enterprise partner, an investor, or a candidate, the voice stays consistent — the tone adapts to the moment.

| We are | We're not |
|---|---|
| ✓ Clear and direct | ✕ Jargon-heavy or corporate-stiff |
| ✓ Confident and optimistic | ✕ Hyped or overpromising |
| ✓ Warm and human | ✕ Cold or transactional |
| ✓ Ambitious but grounded | ✕ Vague or wishy-washy |

### In Practice

**Instead of:** *"We leverage synergistic solutions to optimize stakeholder outcomes."*
**Write:** "We help people move their finances forward."

---

## 08 · Imagery & Graphic Elements

### Photography

- Real, candid people — authentic, optimistic, diverse.
- Natural light, genuine expressions, forward-looking energy.
- Avoid stiff, staged, or generic stock clichés.

### The Diagonal

A dynamic diagonal cut is a recurring device — dividing image from surface, or navy from grey. It reinforces upward motion and gives layouts energy. Keep the angle consistent (roughly 30°, rising left to right).

### The Green Dot

A small green dot or accent shape acts as the brand's signature "spark." Use it to punctuate — beside a sub-brand name, at the end of a statement, or as a bullet — never as decoration for its own sake.

### Iconography

- Simple, geometric line icons with rounded corners.
- Single weight; monochrome, with green reserved for the one element that matters most.

---

## 09 · Sub-Brands

Sub-brands (such as Upbound Digital) extend the master brand. They lock the "upbound" wordmark to a descriptor set in tracked, all-caps type, typically with the descriptor in Upbound Green on dark surfaces. This keeps the family visually unified while giving each unit a clear identity.

**Sub-brand lockup structure:**

```
upbound
D E S C R I P T O R
```

- Descriptor always sits below the wordmark, centered or left-aligned to it.
- Descriptor is all caps, letter-spaced, and never larger than the wordmark.
- Maintain the same clear space and misuse rules as the master logo.

---

## 10 · Quick Reference

The essentials at a glance. When in doubt, come back to this section.

| Item | Value |
|---|---|
| Green | `#B3FF33` |
| Navy | `#35323D` |
| Near Black | `#1A1A1A` |
| Off White | `#F4F4F5` |
| Primary font | Poppins — headlines & display |
| Secondary font | Inter — body & captions |
| Fallback | Arial / Calibri (Office & email) |
| Color rule | 60% dark / 30% neutral / 10% green |
| Green text? | Never on light backgrounds |
| Logo | Black or white wordmark only — as supplied |
| Signature | Diagonal cut + green dot |
| Voice | Clear · confident · optimistic · human |

> **Does it move the audience upward?**
> If yes, it's on brand.

